A Guide to the Ronald E. Carrier Collection, 1965-1998
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Ronald E. Carrier Collection1965-1998
Special Collections, James Madison University
PR 2000-0516B
6 boxes (2.29 linear ft)
This collection consists of administrative papers from the Ronald E. Carrier, president of James Madison University 1971-1998. Also included are selections of speeches he gave to the campus and community while serving as president. A small section of correspondence to Dr. Carrier is also contained in the collection.
Ronald E. Carrier
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Series I was donated by the Office of the President of James Madison University. Series II through IV were transferred to Special Collections in 2010 from the Public Relations Office at James Madison University.
Biographical Information
Ronald E. Carrier began his career at James Madison University in 1971 when the institution was named Madison College. He would continue on his service as President of JMU for twenty-seven years when he retired in 1998. Before he became President of JMU he was the Vice President for Academic Affairs at Memphis State University. Through out the course of his twenty-seven year service to JMU he became known for innovation and tenacity in promoting the institution. During his presidency, Madison College grew from an institution holding 4,000 students, predominantly female and education majors, to a university with 14,000 students. The applications for admission also grew from 3,800 a year to 15,000 a year, while average SAT scores rose from 987 to 1,174.
The name of Madison College changed in 1977 to James Madison University, something that not everyone wanted to do at the time. In October, the Board of Visitors went to the Virginia General Assembly with a name change proposal. A booklet titled “The Case for James Madison University” was printed in a controversial attempt, lobbied by Dr. Carrier and Dr. Ray Sonner, then the Vice President of Public Affairs, to receive a unanimous vote from the Virginia House and Senate. The bill passed through the Virginia House and Senate, and was then signed by Governor Mills Godwin Jr. The JMU community heralded the news and several places around campus were given name changes.
The increase of students and a new name were not the only changes to the institution during Dr. Carrier’s tenure. His presidency expanded the grounds of JMU by more than 100 acres that included expanding the university to the other side of I-81. A total of 40 new buildings were added to the campus, valued at 210 million dollars. The expansion on the other side of I-81 coincided with the proposal of creating a new college of Integrated Science and Technology (CISAT). Dr. Carrier was able to purchase the land with aid from the state. He then supervised and established the new college, worked with staff to create the curriculum, and ensured it met the demands of an increasing technology job market.
Scope and Content
The Carrier Collection contains four separate series of administrative documents relating to the presidency and chancellorship of Ronald E. Carrier at James Madison University. The collection consists of five Hollinger Boxes and one half-Hollinger box. The first series, from a previously compiled collection, consists of miscellaneous university administrative files. It contains many different papers from reports on various aspects of the university to goals and objectives of different university services.
The second series consists of correspondence to and from Dr. Carrier, mostly from his first few years as chancellor of the university, from 1997-1999, with the exception of one letter. These letters are about various subjects, from parents or people at James Madison asking Dr. Carrier questions to requests from various organizations asking Dr. Carrier to come and speak at a certain event. These letters are arranged alphabetically by the person who sent the letter or by the individual receiving the letter. The third series consists of notes and written out speeches that Dr. Carrier gave at various events. These span thirty years, throughout his presidency. Many of the speeches are given to various organizations about education, and many others are given at commencement ceremonies. These speeches are arranged by the date given.
The fourth series contains various miscellaneous materials. The material in these folders is arranged alphabetically by their name or title. The first folder contains speeches that were undated. The second folder contains speech material, which varies from vague notes to material from other speeches or articles. The third folder contains material related to the creation of the Edith J. Carrier Arboretum, which was named after Dr. Carrier’s wife. It has a program of the dedication, and a history of the arboretum. The fourth and fifth folders contain miscellaneous academic papers that mostly are about the “Arabs and Jews”. The sixth folder contains various booklets from events that Dr. Carrier attended. The seventh folder contains various articles about various education matters, as well as one on James Madison himself.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in 4 series:
Miscellaneous Administrative and University Business Files
Correspondence
Speeches
Miscellaneous/Undated Speeches, Administrative, and Academic Papers
Container list starts with the previous collection (series 1), and then goes into the one newly created. As such, the series one is described at the folder level, and series 2-4 are arranged to the item level.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
"Chancellor's Biography." James Madison University - Home. http://www.jmu.edu/chancellor/bio.htm (accessed March 3, 2011).
"JMU - JMU Presidents ." James Madison University - Home. http://www.jmu.edu/centennialcelebration/presidents.shtml (accessed March 3, 2011).
"JMU - Madison College to JMU ." James Madison University - Home. http://www.jmu.edu/centennialcelebration/Madison_JMU.shtml (accessed March 3, 2011).
"JMU Be the Change Profile: Ronald E. Carrier ." James Madison University - Home. http://www.jmu.edu/bethechange/people/carrier.shtml (accessed March 3, 2011).
Roberds, Richard M.. A History of the Founding of the College of Integrated Science and Technology: a Venture in Education Reform. Harrisonburg, Va.: James Madison University, 2005.
Previous Finding Aid
A previous finding aid, consisting of series I was compiled by Marcus Hubbard and Chris Bolgiano, February, 2001 and edited in June, 2008.
Related Material
Carrier Photograph collection - in processing.
Contents List
- Miscellaneous Administrative and University Business Files, 1972-1990, (2 boxes)
  - Administrative Affairs - Goals and Objectives, 1985-89 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Administration and Finance- Goals and Objectives, 1987-88 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Annual Reports and Other Reports (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Audit and Management Review Services, 1986-88 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Business Affairs, 1984-87 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Center for Science and Technology- Missions and Goals, 1988 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - College of Applied Science, Blue Ribbon Panel,1989 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - College of Health and Human Development - Goals and Objectives,1988-91 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Commission on the University of the 21st Century, 1988-89 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Computer Services, 1985-86. (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Disability Services- Objectives, 1985-86 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Educational Development, 1985-86 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Facilities: Dedication of White Hall (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Facilities: Recreation (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Faculty/Staff Relations (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Greater University Commission,1988-90 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - Intercollegiate and Recreational Activities,1986-88 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Issues Report (Box-folder 1:18)
  - Living Sciences - Program Marketing/Student Recruitment Goals,1988-89 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - Master Plan - Goals and Objectives,1985-88 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - New Horizons, 1983 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - Open Dormitories,1971-72 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - Organizational Climate for Teaching and Learning, a survey for the NCRIPTAL (Box-folder 1:23)
  - Research Program on the organizational context for teaching and learning,1988-90. (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Personnel Services, 1985-86 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - Planning and Analysis,1985-86 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - President Ronald Carrier (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Sponsored Research,1986 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Student Affairs - Mission Statement, Goals and Objectives, 1986-88 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Study of Attitudes of JMU Classified Employees,1989-90 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - University Advancement Plan,1987-89 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - University Cabinet - Minutes and Agendas, 1987-90 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Correspondence1997-1999, (3 Folders); Correspondence are arranged alphabetically.
  - To Walid Abushakra May 25 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Walid Abushakra May 26 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - From Tammam Abushakra August 27 1997 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To John Adams September 24 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To J. Brian Atwood November 2 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Dennis Barnes January 18 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Brent Bauman December 9 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To B. Phillip Bigler August 20 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - From Joseph Bordogna July 16 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Joseph Bordogna October 28 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To BOV Member August 5 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Jeffery Bowyer February 15 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To David F. Brakke June 1 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Julie E. Byers September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. June 30 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To John M. Camp, Jr. December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Louis Campanelli March 25 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Mark Carnevale March 25 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Reece Carter December 4 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - From Maria Casey May 6 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Mr. and Mrs. Wallace L. Chandler March 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Kurt E. Chesko April 28 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Dr. Anne B. Crabbe February 11 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Patsy Dean March 24 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Geraldine Dedmon November 16 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To E. Warren Denton November 18 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Richard Dickerson November 11 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Coach Sherman Dillard March 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To The Honorable Barry E. DuVal May 4 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Mr. J. Brannen Edge, III May 10 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To James L. Fisher May 7 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Dr. Judith A. Flohr October 28 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Jim Fraley December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Joanne V. Gabbin September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To O. Leon Garber September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Mrs. Mills E. Godwin, Jr. February 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Dana M. Gorman September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Cristina Hanganu April 8 1999 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - To Donna L. Harper May 3 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Henry H. Harrell January 19 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Coach Gwendolyn Harris November 18 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Coach Patrick R. Henner November 18 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Michael J. Hettinger November 2 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Harvey Hudson December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To John B. Hunt October 28 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Michael Jacobs September 23rd 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To William D. Johnson, IV September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Betty Jolly February 1 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To General John W. Knapp January 22 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Ken Knitter October 19 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To James Lamb November 2 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Leo M. Lambert November 3 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - From Harry Lane, Jr. October 28 1965 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Robert E. LaRose June 15 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Wilmer E. Leatherman October 19 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - From Bill ? October 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Frizzi Linck September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Samuel B. Long III September 23 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To President Petru Lucinschi November 12 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Alan D. MacNutt December 30 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Richard A. Manahan April 30 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Richard A. Manahan October 13 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Jeff Mascott November 5 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Challace Joe McMillin May 3 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To T. Carter Melton May 12 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Carter Melton January 27 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Mark A. Mix March 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Alan Merton March 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Don R. Moore, II December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Suzanne F. Mowbray June 14 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - From J. Michael Mullen December 1 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To John Munford, II November 9 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Elizabeth Neatrouer February 3 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To John B. Noftsinger, Jr. December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Jennifer Norvell November 30 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Bethany Oberst September 28 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Matthew Parker April 26 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Robert Patterson April 28 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Ted Pelikan September 29 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Geoff Polglase March 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - From J. Edward Pruitt, Jr. July 23 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - From Edward Pruitt November 13 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Emily Purdy December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - From J. Carlson Quarles February 12 1985 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Jackson Ramsey September 28 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To John Patrick Rooney October 20 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Linwood Rose April 28 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Linwood Rose March 2 1999 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Lt. Franklin D. Rosenblatt September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - To Dr. Janet C. Rutledge October 28 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Faculty Awards Selection Committee September 15 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Henry J. Schiefer December 1 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Mike Schikman May 12 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - From Robert L. Scott November 3 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Douglas B/ Skelley May 3 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Honorable Alson Smith, Jr. May 31 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To The Honorable and Mrs. Alson Smith, Jr. April 14 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To William D. Smith November 11 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dr. Ray V. Sonner December 2 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dr. Ray V. Sonner November 3 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dr. Diane M. Spresser June 22 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Mrs. Charles Strickler April 28 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Mr. Charles O. Strickler September 11 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Hubert R. Stallard November 6 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Jennifer Thacker July 6/September 10 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Justin B. Thompson April 26 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To William T. Tolley August 12 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dr. Paul E. Torgersen April 13 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Mr. Doug Trout January 5 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - From Doulas G. Trout November 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - From Nancy Jones January 5 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To John VerStandig October 27 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - From John VerStandig October 20 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Senator Stanley C. Walker September 23 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To William T. Walker, Jr. December 22 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dr. W. Lee Ward May 19 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dr. Richard Whitman April 15 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Joyce Wszalek May 4 1999 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - To Dwight Wyse October 19 1998 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Speeches1966-1996, (3 Boxes)
  - “Ethic and Moral Responsibility of Management” February 1966 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “Appointment of a President” November 16 1970 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “The 1960’s and a look at the 1970’s” April 29 1970 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “The Economy and Inflation” September 15 1970 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - No title- given to ETSU Alumni Assoc. January 11 1971 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “Memphis and the Region- Growth and Potential” January 12 1971 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “Convocation Address” February 10 1971 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “Rotary: Code of Ethics Award Banquet” May 3rd 1971 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - “Address- Junior Achievement Banquet” May 17 1971 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty and Administration” September 9 1971 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - “President Carrier’s Report to the Faculty” September 9 1971 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - “Talk to Harrisonburg High School” October 27 1971 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - “The Need for Diversity in Higher Education” March 15 1972 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - “Remarks of the President to the Faculty and Staff” September 4 1972 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - “Dedication Address—Plains School” October 22 1972 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - “Address to: Virginia Association of Broadcasters” February 9 1973 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - “Address to Broadway-Timberville Boy Scout Troop No.1 Court of Honor at Plains Elementary School” April 2 1973 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - “Diversity in Education” April 14 1973 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - “Quality Education” August 27 1973 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “Madison College, 1972-1973—A Review” August 1973 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “The Need for Diversity in Higher Education” September 20 1973 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “Address of Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College to United Fund of Staunton and Augusta County” September 24 1973 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “Presentation of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College Harrisonburg, Virginia” to the American Association of State Colleges and Universities” November 7 1973 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” to Virginia Military Institute Faculty Club February 19 1974 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “The Economics of Scarcity” February 28 1974 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” to Madison College Who’s Who Banquet March 4 1974 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - “Meeting the Educational Challenge” April 5 1974, Also includes previous speech from Memphis State University (Box-folder 3:8)
  - “Address to Faculty” August 30 1974 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - “Address of Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” to Harrisonburg Kiwanis Club October 31 1974 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” for Virginia Accreditation Seminar November 20 1974 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” to Northern Virginia Young Farmers Association December 3 1974 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - “The Elite System within the Egalitarian System” April 11975 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - “Independence Impact on the Consumer” July 23 1975 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College to the Instructional Staff of Albemarle County Schools” August 26 1976 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald Carrier President, Madison College to the Instructional Staff of Lunenburg County Schools” August 30 1976 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - “Needs of the Virginia Institutions of Higher Education” November 5 1976 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - “The End of the Frontier: Address by Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” December 7 1976 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier, Tennessee Gamma ’55 President, Madison College” February 12 1977 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - “College and University Management/College Administration” March 1 1977 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, Madison College” to National Postal Forum South April 19 1977 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - “A Teacher Affects Eternity” August 31 1977 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President James Madison University” to the Annual Meeting of Heritage Savings and Loan Association March 23 1978 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” to the Russell County Teachers’ meeting August 15 1978 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - “The Role of the Public Servant” January 25 1979 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - “Voluntarism: Promoting the Common Good” April 23 1979 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - “Remarks to General Faculty Meeting” May 2 1979 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - “The Roots of the Past and the Direction of the Future” June 10 1979 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - No title- given to Northwestern Virginia Council of the American Association of Retired Persons July 11 1979 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty Norfolk State University” September 16 1979 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - “Higher Education in the 80s—A Need for Action, Not Reaction” 1979 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - “Address to the Math Organizations” March 26 1980 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - No title- Given at the Masonic Sunrise Easter Service, Luray April 6 1980 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - “Leadership in the 1980s” to Virginia Poultry Festival May 16 1980 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty” August 29 1980 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - “The Use of Power”- to James Madison University ROTC December 20 1980 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” to Honors Night at Virginia State University April 20 1981 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - “Values in Education and Leadership for the 80s” to 1981 Conference of Virginia Secondary School Principals June 24 1981 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty” August 27 1981 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” for Fall Faculty Orientation at Northern Virginia Community College September 17 1981 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - “Reagan’s Supply Economics: Theory Revised” October 28 1981 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - “Commencement 1982” Commencement address to Harrisonburg High School June 11 1982 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - “Remarks for Educational Reform” August 10 1982 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E Carrier President James Madison University” to the Virginia Association of Broadcasters June 29 1982 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - “Diamond Anniversary Address” March 13 1983 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” to High Technology Symposium of James Madison University April 28 1983 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty” August 26 1983 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - “Talk to Accounting Honor Society” April 27 1984 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President James Madison University” to the Graduation Ceremonies at Mt. Vernon High School June 4 1984 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - “Notes for Education Conference- Roanoke” August 10 1984 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - “Remarks of Edith J. Carrier First Lady James Madison University” to Harrisonburg Welcome Wagon September 17 1984 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - “Address by: Dr. Ronald E Carrier President James Madison University” to VASA-VSBA Annual Joint Convention October 5 1984 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - No title- about the Military Science Program December 1984 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - No title- remarks for the two Christmas tree lightings December 5 1984 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - “Economic Education: Going Hand in Hand with Economic Growth” to the Virginia Economic Development Seminar December 12 1984 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - “Remarks Honoring Gary Clark” to the Pulaski Chamber of Commerce 1984 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - “Eulogy, Russell M. “Buck” Weaver” February 28 1985 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President James Madison University” to Virginia Chapter 1 Coordinators’ Conference March 20 1985 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University Dedication Ceremony McGraw-Long Hall” March 20 1985 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President James Madison University” to the Business-Industry-Education Seminar April 24 1985 (Box-folder 4:6)